A Guide to the John M. Godown Papers 1849-1935 WLU Coll.0209
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
John M. Godown Papers
1849-1935
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Godown, John M.
Lawton, H. W. (Henry W.)
Batista, P. R., Mrs.
WLU.Coll.0209
.2 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
The materials from Washington and Lee University Special Collections are made available for use in research, teaching, and private study, pursuant to U.S. Copyright law. The user assumes full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to, infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used should be fully credited with the source. Permission for publication of this material, in part or in full, must be secured with the Head of Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. P. R. Batista.
Biographical/Historical Information
John Godown was an 1849 graduate of Washington College. He served in the Union army during the American Civil War under Generals Grant and Sherman and was a member of the Indiana Infantry, 12th Regiment.
Scope and Contents
Included in the papers are diaries, letters, and 25 photographs; also included are letters of several generals and high ranking officers of the American Civil War; Godown's diary is dated 1853-1861; his letters are dated 1861-1865; General Henry Lawton's letters are dated 1886-1899; and the family photographs are dated 1873-1935.
Photographs; Correspondence; Diaries; Batista, P. R., Mrs.
Contents List
- Control Folder (Box-folder 1-1)
- J.M. Godown - Biography and Brief History (Box-folder 1-2)
- J.M. Godown - Vital Documents (Box-folder 1-3)
- J.M. Godown - Diary 1853 (Box-folder 1-4)
- J.M. Godown - Diary 1857-1858 (Box-folder 1-5)
- J.M. Godown Diary 1859-1861 (Box-folder 1-6)
- J.M. Godown Letters 1861 (Box-folder 1-7)
- J.M. Godown Letters 1862 (Box-folder 1-8)
- J.M. Godown Letters 1863 (Box-folder 1-9)
- J.M. Godown Letters 1864-1865 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Letters and Signatures of Civil War Officers (Box-folder 1-11)
- General Lawton's Letters (Box-folder 1-12)
- J.M. Godown - Speech on his services as an officer (Box-folder 1-13)
- Photo Album of the Godown Family (Box-folder 1-14)
- Miscellaneous Godown Photographs and GAR badges (Box-folder 1-15)